Cher Garingan

chernotes.com chergdev@gmail.com 403-975-6702 LinkedIn: /in/cherg Github: /mcherie

A software developer with experience in creating and designing both web and mobile applications. An avid team player and individual contributor, I'm excited about new technology, continuous learning, and innovative advancements.

SKILLS

JavaScript

Node.js

React.js

Express.js

HTML & CSS

Redux

Python

Pygame

Ruby on Rails

TypeScript

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

Knex.js

Firebase

Netlify

Heroku

Git

Mobile

Agile, Scrum Bitbucket, JIRA

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

OnResearch, Inc., Aug 2020 - Present

- Responsible for the front-end development of projects.
- Released a benchmark survey for clients using React, Hooks, and styled-components.
- Built the front-end services that crunches data and deliver business insights through different graphical representations such as charts and graphs. Tech and tools used include D3.js, Victory.js, and Material Design.

Full-Stack Developer

NorthOne, Inc., Aug 2020 - Dec 2020

- Worked with design, product, QA, and rest of the engineering team to create and launch the mobile banking application on both iOS and Android platform using React-Native and TypeScript
- Created the web onboarding banking application using React and Redux
- Responsible for adding new features, improvements and integrations, on-going maintenance, and bug-fixes for weekly releases in an agile development environment

Equipment & Logistics Tech

The Michener Institute, Sept 2017 - Aug 2020

 Provide equipment set-up, recording of student performances, and instructor and equipment support for Heart & Stroke Foundation courses (ACLS, PALS, NRP, PEARS)

IT Intern

World Health Organization (WHO), Summer 2012

 Generated and maintained a SharePoint worksite and Excel database of finance and procurement documents of the IT department

PROJECTS

Pygame - TicTacToe

The classic tic-tac-toe game that can be played with either two players or single player against the computer. Game created with Python and Pygame

BridgeBot

A SlackBot application with a backend server (Node.js, Express.js) that interacts with Slack API and FireStore (NoSQL, Firebase). The front-end web-app (React, Redux) is a poll form generator and presents results in pie charts.

Gamebox

A social games platform hosting party games to be played with friends. Current game included is Wing-It, where users can join a game through a Room Code generated by a host. Tech used include Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, React.js, and Socket.io

Clippit

Å resource wall for users to post, share, like, and rate topic resources. Tech used include JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, JQuery, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Knex.js

EDUCATION

Mount Royal University, Calgary, AB

Advanced Software Development Bridge School, Toronto, ON	Oct - Dec 2019
Full Stack Web Development Lighthouse Labs, Toronto, ON	May - Aug 2019
Bachelor of Science	2010-2013